Service Workers Union - SEIU Local 82 Oral History Project OHP014
People's Archive, MLK Library
Service Workers Union - SEIU Local 82 Oral History Project
1993-1997
People's Archive, MLK Library
OHP014
1.25 Linear feet
2 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Transcripts Scope and Contents Materials in this series include transcripts of the interviews. There is no transcript for 14-03. Series 2: Interviews Scope and Contents Materials in this series include master copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies for audio recordings 14-07 and 14-11. All others have only one copy. There is no tape for 14-13.
Biographical / Historical
The Service Employees International Union has always sought to organize workers in a wide range of occupations. Beginning with janitors and elevator operators when it formed in 1921, SEIU soon added security guards, window cleaners, health care workers, office workers and public sector employees. By 1968, the union represented service workers in over 100 occupations around the nation.
Custodial History
Service Employees International Local 82 conducted these interviews between 1993 and 1997, and donated the tapes and transcripts to the Library in the late 1990s. There is no deed of gift for this collection, but all interviewee releases are granted to the Library.
Scope and Contents
Between 1993 and 1997, Service Employees International Union Local 82, the DC branch of a union representing mainly custodial workers, conducted a total of 13 oral history interviews with union members as part of the Service Workers' Oral History and Education Project. Interviewees were current and former union members of all ages, some who had taken part in union leadership. Topics include work experiences, union politics, interviewee experiences in union leadership, and health.
Oral History; Labor unions; Health; Politics and government; Service industries workers
- Series 1: Transcripts
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include transcripts of the interviews. There is no transcript for 14-03.
  - Elizabeth Kennedy, 1995 August 5 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fred Arrington, 1995 October 7 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fred Arrington, 1995 October 7 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Herbert Thomas, 1995 October (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mary Martin (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Leslie Lane, 1995 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alta Cook, 1995 October 28 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Louis Bankett, 1995 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jay Nessey, 1995 November 13 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Arline Neal, 1995 June 10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Teresa Rivera (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Marion Lewis, 1997 February 17-1997 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series 2: Interviews
  Materials in this series include master copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies for audio recordings 14-07 and 14-11. All others have only one copy. There is no tape for 14-13.
  - Elizabeth Kennedy, 1995 August 5 (Box 2, Folder 14-02)
  - Elizabeth Kennedy, 1995 August 5 (Box 2, Folder 14-02)
  - Myrna Mobley, 1995 September 30 (Box 2, Folder 14-03)
  - Fred Arrington, 1995 October 7 (Box 2, Folder 14-04)
  - Fred Arrington, 1995 October 7 (Box 2, Folder 14-04)
  - Herbert Thomas, 1995 October (Box 2, Folder 14-05)
  - Mary Martin (Box 2, Folder 14-06)
  - Leslie Lane, 1995 November 29 (Box 2, Folder 14-07)
  - Alta Cook, 1995 October 28 (Box 2, Folder 14-08)
  - Louis Bankett, 1995 November 3 (Box 2, Folder 14-09)
  - Louis Bankett, 1995 November 3 (Box 2, Folder 14-09)
  - Jay Nessey, 1995 November 13 (Box 2, Folder 14-10)
  - Arline Neal, 1995 June 10 (Box 2, Folder 14-11)
  - Arline Neal, 1995 June 10 (Box 2, Folder 14-11)
  - Teresa Rivera (Box 2, Folder 14-12)